Thank you very much.
Welcome everyone for joining.
The title of this panel is Post
Digital Creativity in Honor
and Their Acknowledged Communities.
And the panelists will be taken by the
and myself on occurrence.
And we're very excited to give you
a little taste of three literary genres
that have been circulating online,
but they haven't received
any sustained attention
within the community yet.
And our overarching proposal
is that to include Ayelet for Ayelet
research to include these
and other genres, in part because they're
very interesting in these cells,
but also because it can help us understand
other electronic data and situate
and understandably
so, this is how it's going to go.
We will each briefly introduce our
by demonstrating an example of it.
Then afterwards we will do a short Menti
questionnaire with you.
Then we'll go into our case studies
a little bit deeper.
But by explaining the angle
of the digital distribution.
And finally
we will have time for discussion
where we are particularly interested in
the role of both digital channels
in your own work and life.
And in our proceedings
paper, we go a little bit further
into the history
and details of the
was that we don't have time for today,
so you can always read that later
if you're interested.
But for now you first
get to learn about taking bikes
literary genre, which is save stories. So.
Yes,
let me just share my screen
and bear with me today.
This is the first time
I'm reading from a script,
so if I stumble, it's
because I'm not used to this.
Okay. Let's go.
I'm here today to talk to you about sim
stories, otherwise known in the community
as SIM Lit,
which is a portmanteau of sim literature.
Sims stories are a variety of vernacular
digital literary
practice produced by members of The Sims
gaming community.
They're multi-modal and combine written
text with images created by the writer
or in this case, the player writer,
engaging with The Sims game
engine and taking screenshots.
While The Sims gaming
franchise has received some,
though I would argue not enough
scholarly attention.
Sims stories have gone unrecognized
within academia,
outside a handful of articles
about the effects of participation
on the literary literacy rates of teenage
sim storytellers.
In these cases, Sims stories are often
designated as a variety of fans.
Fiction.
In many ways, this is understandable.
All Sims story writers are also
fans of the game, and for those unfamiliar
with digital literature,
there are few other ways to describe
Sims stories succinctly
in a way that is understandable
to a mainstream audience.
However, using the fan fiction
nomenclature to describe sim
stories reduces the breadth of practices
within The Sims story term.
In my research, either four distinct,
though frequently
overlapping varieties of writing
the first varieties of cinema story
are emerging, created by interaction
with The Sims games themselves.
Within the community.
This is known as sim or game driven
storytelling.
The most common of these narratives
surround gaming challenges, where a player
writer attempts to meet goals preset
by another community member.
The Legacy Challenge is
one of the most popular
of these challenges and on screen now
we can see an example of one such story
The Evergreen Legacy.
Like all legacy challenges,
the Evergreen Legacy
follows
ten generations of a single sim family.
So in literary terms,
all legacy challenges are family sagas.
Looking at the evergreen legacy,
we can see the common format for a sim
story.
SIM stories are serialized, released
in what player writers
call chapters or episodes
clicking through to a chapter.
We can see the layout of a typical
sim story as well.
In game stream, screenshots are placed
above with prose below,
and the amount of prose can differentiate
depending on the writer.
This writer is particularly verbose,
with multiple paragraphs
attached to each image,
but this can be extremely short as well.
There's a variation between what
I would call prose writing and straight
commentary, where they just described
what's happening in the game.
In this layout, we also find the overlap
between Sims stories and Let's Play Media,
a hugely popular form of content
characterized by documentation of gameplay
with commentary from the player.
The Evergreen Legacy
is what I would categorize as an original.
Let's play the first of the four forms.
Transformative.
Let's plays, however, are also
a part of The Sims story umbrella.
I use transformative here,
in the same manner
as the organization of transformative
works to denote the taking
of something extant
and turning it into something
with a new purpose, sensibility,
or mode of expression affectively.
Fanfiction.
An example of transformative
Sims Let's Play is SIM Brother,
which is currently on the screen.
Originally run by staff of The Sims
fan site SIM Zone, SIM Brother mimics
the format of the popular 90s and 2000
TV show Big Brother, placing nine sims
placing $0.09
into a single household,
who are then voted out
by SIM Brothers readers.
In this case, the SIM contestants
are virtual copies of real celebrities.
Series one includes Eminem, Tony Blair,
and Tom cruise,
making SIM Brother
a case of emergent real person fanfiction.
Outside of emergent narratives,
Sims stories can also be pre-determined,
with the story written first,
then stage within The Sims games
for illustrative purposes.
These stories
share similarities with Mashima
machinima movies made by utilizing game
engines and nationalists,
which is the same in the format of paneled
comics.
Sims stories differ from these forms,
however, in their utilization
of writing in conjunction with the game
engine illustrations.
This variety of works
I've subcategories as original
and transformative Sims fiction have less.
A lesser is a beautiful example
of an original SIM section work
as skewing the norm of sim stories
being accompanied by prose.
A letter is instead
written as a drama piece, with in-game
staging that impersonates
a live stage performance.
As I scroll, we can see the ways
in which images and writing are used
in tandem to create the overarching story,
with lack of written text
used to establish atmosphere
and to create poignancy.
The same technique can be found in Strange
Town, Here
We Come, a work of transformative
Sims fiction written over two decades.
In this piece, Author Strange
Tomato has woven the intricate
and intricate, intricate narrative
surrounding the occupants
of a pre-made neighborhood, effectively
a game save pre-populated with Sims
by the developers that uses emergent
and predetermined storytelling.
This stock, the short story being shown
sneak out with a failure, is an offshoot
of the main narrative,
in which the author has staged
the events that may have occurred
between two Sims during an in-game
interaction that the player is unable
to follow in actual gameplay.
This staging is crucial
for its categorization as fiction, as
the events are impossible
to capture in-game and rather abruptly.
That concludes my introductory piece.
I'll now hand over to Hannah.
Thank you very much.
I want to introduce you to Norwegian
Sign language
poetry and Bala
share my screen in the chat.
Please give me a thumbs up
if you use a sign language.
Any sign language,
but make it a handshake
if it's in a region sign.
Yay! We have someone who knows about.
Well, don't worry that there's not more,
because the problem that
I've chosen to show you is very simple.
I love it, and it's very easy
to understand without knowing
Norwegian sign language
or any sign language for that matter,
and for those who don't have access
to watching it on the screen right now,
I will audio describe it afterwards.
So this was biathlete
performing his bow on ten list,
which means old to sign language.
So he's wearing black clothes
and he stands in front of a soft
yellow background,
which also had images of signing on it.
And in the performance
he uses the sign for signing,
which is is open
hands alternating up and down.
It also in multiple directions,
looking very happy
to be talking to people in his language.
Afterwards,
he admires and kisses his own hands.
That makes it possible
for him to communicate, and then stretches
his arms out to the audience.
So in sign language poetry,
sign language is used in a creative way
for a literary effect, and
in the few sources that are specifically
on our reach in sign language poetry,
practitioners tend to highlight
that the poetry contributes to
showing the identity and status of
Norwegian Sign Language as a language.
Now I am learning Norwegian
Sign Language.
So of course I looked up the poetry
and I found these and other poems,
and I was really struck by the overlap
it had with electronic literature.
And I feel like my background
in electronic literature
has given me the tools
to situate and analyze
Norwegian Sign Language poetry,
but I haven't been exposed
to it within our community.
So, for example, in Elit, we're proficient
in thinking about it in terms of lineage,
lineages and inspirations.
And similarly, we can link
poetry in different sign language
to avant garde researches.
Concrete poetry.
Because of the semi
iconic nature of the language.
And although each sign language
has its own rules,
poetry does allow for experiments.
It is playing with the shape
of language and medium,
as we do in init or in other elit.
So and this play occurs very multimodal.
Not only is the language itself
already multimodal, but there's always so
the use of offline performances,
background music
and then online distribution
in varied spaces.
More on that later.
So it is no surprise then, that
in sign language research,
researchers have noted
that sign language poetry can contribute
to developing a concept of poetry
that is beyond the printed page,
which is a very familiar claim
for it as well.
So I will leave you with that for now
and give
the unmute button to Sarah,
who will introduce you to Kate.
With Richard
I have Revan,
which is going to quickly share my screen.
Okay,
I'm working with multiple screens
and I haven't really tried showing
an archived gateway to Richard before,
so let's see how it goes.
Going to copy Hannah's great idea
and ask you to quickly
drop a heart emoji in the chat
if you know what K-pop is,
and double hearts
if you've come across gateway traitor.
While you do that, I'd like to show you
sections of Twitter in action.
These are sections from one of the zombie
horror slash murder mystery
Twitter eaters,
which are K-pop, Twitter or K-pop.
Twitter fiction by user 17.
Train to Busan an ex user writer
who ran for large scale
interactive and participatory,
doubly layered or real people
fictions, blending fandom knowledge
with a knowledge of adapted source text.
So these would be gay Twitter rituals
that had characters from a K-pop fandom,
but also at the same time,
a popular movie or a popular novel
that the readers would have to go back to
to look for clues to solve the mystery.
I picked this example to show you
how by 2020, the general had
already evolved into bringing in reader
insert characters within the live story.
User 1722 would transform
all followers
slash readers into characters,
creating a story with an average of 200
live and interacting
characters over a series of days.
This one is called 17
Train to Pusan
and we shall go to the master thread.
As you can see, I'm clicking through the
archive for the master thread,
but if you were playing this live,
it would be a simpler thread.
You were invited to join
the 1722 richer
by an announcement, and everybody
who signed up would get individual
tickets and seats via train, both
ticketing system created by the user.
And once you were on board,
you had to follow certain rules.
There would be voting periods for polls
that would decide which track the story
would take at any point of time,
and the readers would get at least
two clues to help them choose answers
and solve the mysteries.
There are 17 members in.
There are 13 members
in the K-pop group 17, and
you would have to save as many members
as possible.
And as soon as there are no member
characters, the game is over.
And how do you really do that?
Let's see.
The readers would get clues
in a separate thread.
The thread feature of Twitter
is great for this, and in this way
you would be provided with timestamped
clues, complex codes, and
you would have to work together.
And since the boats are defined,
are defined by the number of people.
So this one has for 30 votes.
And as you can see,
it was quite close in terms of voting
because you had to let
one of the 17 members
on the train when there are zombies
on the platform already,
and you had to do it thinking,
which one is the one favored by the clues?
Once you choose
a particular answer to the poll,
depending on most of the readers
deciding for a majority option,
and this kind of discussion would happen
with a designated hashtag.
The hashtag for this one was hashtag 17.
Train to Busan.
Then the story would continue in small
fictional paragraphs,
and there would also be news
announcements.
There are newspaper cuttings
and thread as well.
Every level would have polls
that the readers would have to solve,
and the readers at the same time
also had to survive on their own.
So if you were in a particular quote
that was infested
by zombies,
your survival rate would go down.
Coach 11 survival is -1% at some point,
but they were wise
because they sacrificed themselves
so that more 17 characters could live.
There are also lots of hidden clues,
whether on tickets
or choosing the wrong option in the poll.
Sometimes there would be no clues
for the poll
and you would just have to choose wisely.
Let's see if there's something else.
Yes, there was also a customer support
announcement thread where the reader
characters, that is, the followers
of the Twitter Richer had a chance
to figure out their own fates,
and they would have lots of freedom
to go about and do what they want.
For example, a stray passenger spotted
on the train's roof above coach eight.
There were also passengers
who could not get a ticket,
and they would be hanging
from one of the doors.
On the train.
A cunning passenger
is baiting a new passenger
into going towards the dangerous coaches.
So all of these discussions
that would be happening in
the thread would be reported
in the customer service announcements.
Now, I have both authored Twitter
and participated in Kate with Richmond.
Been in fandoms including Hallyu fandoms
who've made use of Twitter
for creativity and community.
The rise of Twitter paralleled Hallyu 2.0
or the new Korean
Wave, the spread of Korean pop culture
through social media and smartphones.
However, there is little
or at most cursory attention
given to gateway, whether it be
within Elite or Twitter research,
or even within fandom studies.
The act, which is treated as individual,
unconnected occurrences
rather than a highly active for an actor.
I argue that Kate, with its enthusiasm
for parody, adaptation and fanfiction,
as well as what Walia
et al call in this context nano
linguistics best presents
the original spirit of Twitter,
while also developing the collaborative
potential
of the diffusing authority and authorship
in new and playful ways.
And this is where we start doing
the fundamental stuff.
Over to your Tekken.
Yes, we thought it would
be nice
to take a small poll of our audience,
which may or may not be exploited
for research purposes at a later date.
There's no promises here, but if you would
like to join the poll, we have a URL.
If you go to Montcalm and input the code,
or if you use the QR code,
it will load straight in.
I'll give you two minutes to do that.
I cannot see the chat anymore
so I won't ask for a multi-year yet
when you're done.
I can see five
people are in, so I'll just wait for that
to tick up to somewhere around 20,
hopefully.
Nine, 1011.
We should have had some hold
music for this section to.
Remember, I know.
My chance to promote 17 and I missed it.
How could you?
Okay,
we're at 17 so I think that's good to go.
You can still join as we go on as well.
So the first question
on the mental meter, have you heard
any of our case studies before.
This is multiple choice.
So you can pick as many as you know.
Or if you know none at all.
Oh, oh, people have heard of some stories.
This is great.
Oh, I see lighting the gateway
director person here.
Oh, two people 300,
this is very nice.
Hey, we've got 18 out of 20
of those last two people.
Oh, we're almost there.
One more.
Maybe not,
but that's amazing.
A lot more of you have sim stories
than I thought you would have.
I don't know if it's the same for Kate,
which in sign language poetry.
This is more than I expected.
You guys are cool.
I think this is about what I expected,
but I suspect
that it's mainly ASL.
That's poetry that people know about,
but I'm not sure because that's not
in the. Oh,
okay.
So on next round of questions are on
whether you consider our case studies
as a form of digital literature.
So we'll go into this.
Not all people are still replying.
This is so fun.
I love that it's real time.
Okay, so on to the next question.
Do you think Sims stories are a variety
of digital literature?
Yes, no, or a secret third thing?
Well we haven't. No.
I'd be fascinated to hear from you
in the discussion section.
A secret third thing is very popular.
Okay.
Next, do you think sign language
poetry is a variety
of digital literature?
I love the secret 13, folks.
I'm scared
might have skewed our results
a little bit.
Interesting sign language.
Poetry is a secret.
Third sing. Hannah,
how do you feel about this?
Yeah, I think I don't know if a secret
they're a thing to people.
Meant maybe.
Or on the one. Yes.
Or the other? No.
I like it, though.
If you chose a secret third thing.
We would love to hear from you
in the discussion section as well.
I'd love to hear
from nose and secrets
and things, actually.
And finally,
do you think, hey, Twitter is a variety
of digital literature?
Oh yeah.
Look at this though.
Oh, Zahra Sahara, you picked the piece of
digital literature
all those years in the fandoms
they pay off.
Okay.
And now we have an open question
where we'd like to know if any of these
case studies have reminded you of a type
of post digital vernacular creativity
that you're involved
with outside of your work?
So is there anything that you personally
consider digital literature
that you haven't heard of talked openly
within the electronic literature
community?
I think with this one,
you can submit your own answers
and they'll peer
as a beautiful word cloud.
Or you can say no.
Oh. Do I like Substack there?
Yeah, Substack is an interesting
one, is definitely
whatever happens,
whatever happens on Tumblr, I agree.
Backs.
Oh, Homestuck roast code language AOC.
We did predict that the no would be big.
Yeah. Yes.
AOC is so good.
I think this really brings
into question the overlap between
digital literature and fanfiction.
I think it's fascinating. I.
Multiform what is outside.
Wikipedia.
Dating sims.
Yes, especially the ones that
come on your mobile now.
Comment thread fiction. Yes.
Interactive party games? Yes.
If we all the other three
can take over the novel.
Lyric videos.
Yeah.
AI to the co-taught. Yes.
And I know exactly who submitted that one.
Camilla.
Scrolling comics.
Yes, I agree with so many of these.
Okay, thank you very much everyone.
I think we'll call it there
because I can see this never ending.
But this is great.
Group chat.
Running jokes. Yes.
I love so many of these
because what I would define
as emergent narratives.
But that's.
Dwarf Fortress narratives. Yes.
Oh, I have so much to say about that.
Okay.
In that case,
I think it's time for the second half.
Hannah, are you taking over
for a brief introduction,
or am I going straight into thinking?
So distribution formats
and infrastructure
can become integral parts of how work
or how a general functions in Illit?
I'm sure that I'm not telling you anything
new there.
To the extent that the difference
between like born digital
in marks and digital distribution
can be blurred.
So we thought that would be a good angle
to talk a little bit more about.
Each of our was and we'll go
in the same order as we did before.
So take in your up again.
Hey, so since stories
were originally conceived
during the launch of the first Sims game
by Max's, the game's developer, as a way
of leveraging participatory culture
to increase the game's market share.
As such, the first appearance of Sims
stories was on the official
The Sims websites, where they were
originally called Family Albums.
Here, users could upload their family
albums and reads
the albums at other players,
and we can see
the beginnings of the
form as we currently know it
via captures in
the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine
of the exchange of exchanging stories,
in particular
continued on official sites
for both the second and third sim games.
The Sims community,
however, has always been
nebulous, spread through a plethora
of fansites, forums, blogs
and later social network platforms,
and now social media platforms.
Something you may have spotted
in my earlier section,
which showed player writers
using self-hosted websites,
WordPress and Dream width as distribution
methods.
It's also common for Sims storytellers
to advertise their works in community
hubs, such as Before the rise of Tamla
and Twitter Live Journal.
As a result,
we could accurately describe Sims stories
as a form of what Scott
Redbird describes as network writing,
writing that takes advantage of networked
computing to facilitate distribution.
This has made studying
sim stories particularly difficult,
as many historical works
are now effectively lost.
Media.
Following the closures of older web
services, including the official
Sims websites themselves, and
hosting providers like GeoCities.
As a result, many previously active
communities
are now little more than traces
in the Wayback Machine, accessible via
luck or what
I call hyperlinked snowboarding,
where an accessible community is found
and surfed through until all links
have been tested
and many of these do fail.
These captures,
however, tend to be partial missing
images, linked pages,
and frequently context.
We can see the impact of partial impartial
capture here in the saga of Doctor
Evil Sims, a work of original Sims
autofiction based on the writer's
experiences
of electroconvulsive convulsive therapy.
While some less young odes,
depending on your choice and terminology,
remain intact.
As we can see on the first note here,
many more are far from complete,
as we can see from reading further.
I'll just let it load.
Hopefully it takes a long time
to access this work, I think because it's
just that old.
So as you can see here,
it takes a long time to load,
but many of the images
when it comes through are missing.
And this removes a lot of context
for the pieces
and makes judgment of the works
more difficult.
Archival efforts within the community
are few and far between and distant.
Well,
given the diffuse nature of the community
and its relative obscurity,
the most notable act of rogue archival
committed by the community
is an archive of hundreds
of Sims stories
scraped from The Sims Tulkarm exchange
when it was taken offline.
Well, this sounds sizable.
It's only a fraction of the hundreds
of thousands of works
originally available on The Sims two,
and the stories hosted
there were again
only a fraction of the community's output.
This begs the question who decides
what exactly is a digital literary
work worthy of preservation?
And beyond this, how do we, as digital
literary practitioners
keep track of and document
the plenty tude of born digital forms
created by communities well outside
the boundaries of the ello communities
that may have no idea
what electronic literature is.
For some time
now, we've lived in a postage society
where avant garde practice
can be performed by everyday people
using proprietary software
owned by massive tech conglomerates.
By failing to account for these practices,
we miss important contributions
to literary culture and further than that,
digital digital culture as a whole.
For example, it
was only in performing
my research on sim stories,
which I was lucky enough
to have an awareness
of from my participation in the community
as a teenager that I discovered
the emergent narrative varieties
of same story classifiers.
Let's place.
This is significant
as the current popular history
of Let's Play Media on the web argues
for its emergence on the Something Awful
forums,
a male dominated community, in 2004.
But when we take sim stories into account,
we instead find an alternative
origin point in a female dominated gaming
community four years earlier.
As such, overlooking the contributions
of vernacular digital creative communities
can lead to inaccurate,
if not entirely false, knowledges.
And with that, I'll hand over time
when I stop sharing.
Thank you very much.
So in addition to in-person events,
we can find recorded Norwegian
Sign language poetry online.
So let's go back to the list.
The poem that we watched before.
You can see it again.
So this poem was originally published
on a DVD
of Norwegian Sign language poetry,
which is no longer available.
And the reason that we can watch it
well is because it's on the website.
Which
is a educational research
for sign language
users. And.
You could find it
still as a YouTube video
because it was part
of the promotional material
for the original DVD
that's no longer available.
And the reason you would maybe be watching
or looking for its on YouTube
is because people also self-publish.
Self-publish their poems on YouTube.
Here.
Something's
clearly gone wrong with the replay,
but this is supposed to be a poem
about corona and the experience
of social distancing.
It's less boring page,
so these replayable videos have media
specific for that influence the work.
Being able to rewatch poems
means that you can notice
nuances and details that you couldn't
really expect from a live audience
who is seeing it once.
And of course, it also influences
the creation process,
because it's making it easier for authors
to save their ideas
and to develop their performance,
which is something that
poets of Wittenberg
had had access to for centuries.
Now, platform for is also influence
how we perceive Norwegian
sign Language poetry.
So when I search
for Posy on YouTube,
I'm a bit frustrated
because it often gives me results
that are in other sign languages.
But YouTube has translated
the titles of these videos to Norwegian,
just erasing the linguistic
and literary differences.
For example, when I've for it here
we find the poem
that I've been showing you.
But we also find the caterpillar,
which is a poem
in visual vernacular
that is translated by.
The titles translate to Norwegian,
and ironically, also a short
which has a
translated title
that means a sign language, universal,
which compares ASL to BSL
and YouTube, tries
to account for what they are doing
with this translation
by putting a little tag next to it
that says that the spoken
language is English, which is also wrong
because it isn't spoken English
or different sign languages.
And I point this out to say that
there is this tension between promoting
Norwegian Sign Language online
through poetry, while also needing
to rely on these platforms
that diffuse the languages
between each other.
Now, the dispersed nature of obligation
without, like ESPN in these
different platforms, has also led
to online collection practices.
For example,
the Deaf Church in Norway
has been involved in developing
sign language
poetry as part of their liturgy,
which is also reflected in what
is available in terms of documentation.
They have a website
that preserves about 100 Christians
and hymns through
recording and online display.
And since I have researched either
databases in my PhD,
I am very excited to dig deeper
into the Norwegian
Sign language poetry databases
and see how these practices compare.
Stop sharing.
But today I want to leave you with this.
I think the L in the last decade has made
great strides in terms of including
non-English works of digital literature,
which is really in the field,
and in recent years also to include
third generation electronic literature
to increase
our understanding of digital creativity.
And I believe that
including the different digital practices
of various sign language poetries
in different sign languages
similarly has this promise
to help us better understand
the fields.
And then I will give the floor to seven.
Hello again.
Okay, give me a second.
Yes. So as we saw, Gatewood, registries
usually begin
as a short promise treated by an anonymous
X account.
This could be either one or more person
handling the account.
The 1,720% account did share
that they were at least two admins.
The account usually has a username
related to the fandom.
This one is related directly
to the name of the story itself, and
gives rise to a form of
blending fanfiction with large scale,
interactive storytelling, as we show.
As we saw combining elements from Choose
Your Adventure stories and RPGs
with large scale funded participation.
This free interactive fiction format,
though you can think deeply about
is X free anymore, often features
a further diffusion of authorship
by featuring other
X users as readers who decide crucial plot
developments and often even feature
as characters in a story.
This would mean that
the characters are part of even
how the story or the narrative design
is created in 1722.
This meant that a lot of the reader
characters were also archiving
data, creating Excel sheets,
network graphs, etc.
this isn't.
This is an Excel sheet screenshot
about which users and readers
are in which coaches,
because they would also have to work
together
and compete with the other coaches.
The platform affordances.
Oh, this meant that the readers
would have multiple roles
at the same time, that of secondary
authors, readers, players, and characters.
The platform affordances effects
provide the tools for such
a participation, and Kate Richer utilizes
tweet threads
like this one.
Polls, as we saw linked multimedia,
hashtags, replies and go to tweet
functions to transform massively popular
mystery of SoC med, which is social media.
A soft Mets look like this
or horror genre is into mobile
friendly, fast paced, bite sized, fandom
specific puzzle stories.
This one is outcast,
which was posted in 2018 initially.
This is a revamped version
of just for showing you how it looked.
It was an interactive BS horror SoC
met by User Flirtatious,
which began trending on X,
racking up for 20 K followers
within a few days, and a worldwide
trending hashtag hashtag BDS.
Outcast beyond obvious
honor blending horror Chat
Fix and Med Outcast showcases how Gateway
Ratio blends active fandom presence.
You can see 52 K likes, 29 K
reposts,
and a bunch of people in the hashtag.
Even now,
it shows us how engagement features
present on the flat
platform to design, rate, and participate
in the story encouraged
Gateway to Richer,
which is also defined by a fixed timeline.
We saw this with Train to Busan as well.
I think the whole story ends
within a week.
As the story.
The story is also updated
live and readers participate in the plot
development by voting on polls
to change the course of the story.
Because Train to Busan was set in Korea
on a train to San.
The timings usually followed KST,
which meant people had to stay awake
or wake up to be part of the story.
Updates.
It was super exciting.
What else?
One of the other, A, was posted
by the same users as Train to Busan
was 17 Masquerade Hotel.
This one was 17,
but imagine they are in Masquerade Hotel.
But the plot works as
And Then There Were None by Agatha
Christie,
which meant people had to actually go read
Masquerade Hotel
and And Then There Were None.
And the readers actually did all of that
at the same time.
A lot of the clues,
would
ask the users to go check out the fan app.
I think it was weavers in 20 2417,
and you had to keep track of what
the characters, but also the 17 members
in real life are posting.
But this shows us that gateway represents
a development of BFS
and OC original character,
or why in your name fiction
into a large scale interactive
storytelling genre, which in its function
may not be limited to K-pop,
but a fluid format that would work for
other fandoms and even original fiction,
depending on reader mobilization
capabilities, instead of treating stories
as singular occurrences.
The inclusion of the as viable illiterate
shed light on an otherwise under
acknowledged
digital storytelling format and practice.
I will share links in the chat
for those who are interested
to check out these threads,
and I look forward to the discussion.
Thank you.